

Dr. Marc Lange

Team Lead, Data Science, Business Intelligence



Hamburg, Germany



+49 171 110 39 21



marc@lange-data.org

https://github.com/Vassago1911

About me —

problem solver analytical, creative, abstract Automation, Prediction, Analysis.. no kind of data I can't simulate or model into a Aha! Regression, that will work for years even without me :)

fluent in python, sql, latex, zsh, english, german
Blender, Numpy, Pandas, MEX, Scikit-Learn, (Tensorflow), BERT, Tesseract, Tableau, Matomo, Google Ads, ...

models in data, geometry, dynamical systems, algebra

Natural Language Processing, (Realtime) Audio/Video Processing, automated understanding, Chatbots, Revenue Prediction, Budget Optimisation

experienced with developing people, relationships, models, processes

team lead experience, consultant experience, lots of experience in educating people, sometimes in things I've just researched a week ago myself :)

Skills ———

Education

2011-2015 Doktor (Ph.D.) "magna cum laude" Hamburg

Majoring in Mathematics, Minor Physics

2005-2011 Diplom "sehr qut" Hamburg

Majoring in Mathematics, Minor Computer Science

-2005 Abitur Schleswig-Holstein

Specialized in mathematics and chemistry.

Languages: German (native) English (fluent)

Theses

2015 PhD Multiplicative structures and involutions on algebraic K-theory 2011 Diplom Examples of Involutions on Algebraic K-Theory of Bimonoidal Categories

Experience

2018-2019 Tech Lead, BI / Data Science

AppLike GmbH, Hamburg

- doubled the margin share of revenue by mathematical optimisation of our bids
- educated one working student in tracking, reporting and modelling (Python, SQL, Elastic, Machine Learning)
- define half year goals for Team BI
- presented on our sales event for our Top10 partners
- joined career fairs to approach business and tech applicants
- attended a Sandler Workshop with the Sales-Team
- filled in as Product Owner for a backend-team in March 2018
- advising a master thesis in AppLike to synthetically generate fraudulent behaviour, so we can find new security holes - will finish in July

2016-2017 Business Intelligence (BI) Analyst

AppLike GmbH, Hamburg

- center between tech and business: tracking and reporting
- communicating with external partners for integrations e.g. Appsflyer, Singular, King, Playrix, etc.
- · occasionally explaining new tech features to business
- push a business request to the backend informally when efficient and needed

2007-2015 Various Tutoring jobs

University of Hamburg

• instructed classes in Linear Algebra, Set Theory, Mathematics for Physicist

Other information As a mathematician and a general tech enthusiast I am not fixed to specific areas of application. Currently my business expertise stems from a well-scaling business model in mobile marketing for the gaming sector, but I can see myself in contexts which are more scientific, more compassionate, or also more classic than this digital sector.

I generally make it a point to look for a diverse and kind environment of colleagues and contribute to that myself. I bring in some diversity expertise from contributing in university to the "AG Queer Studies". At the yearly Chaos Communication Congress I keep myself informed and inspired on current scientific developments as well as the ethics of tech. Finally I usually try to code one or two new papers (usually from arXiv, e.g. https://arxiv.org/abs/1901.02878v1) on machine learning in my spare time, so I will tell you when the most promising AI-development comes.

Hobbies: Gaming (Pen and Paper (DnD), PC (Starcraft, Mass Effect)), Sports (Yoga, Gym, BJJ (retired)), US-Series to keep my English current

Salary expectation: 80.000€+